<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="xdg_toplevel_drag_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright 2023 David Edmundson &lt;davidedmundson@kde.org&gt;

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="xdg_toplevel_drag_manager_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="Move a window during a drag">
      This protocol enhances normal drag and drop with the ability to move a
      window at the same time. This allows having detachable panels similar to
      what desktop environments done with subwindows.

      A typical workflow would be:
      - The user starts a drag from a special "tab" which may be dragged out
        of its panel.
      - Once the user released the button, if the user dragged outside of the
        panel the "tab" becomes a toplevel window.
      - If the user dropped onto another tab, the panel handles the drop as it
        sees fit.

      This protocol is not limited to this one use-case; a compositor could
      advertise the protocol even if it does not support this particular
      combination. However a compositor that does not support this would be
      limited to handling it as a regular drop.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the xdg_toplevel_drag_manager_v1 object">
        Destroys the xdg_toplevel_drag_manager_v1 object. This does not
        affect any remaining objects created from this manager.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="get_xdg_toplevel_drag">
      <description summary="get an xdg_toplevel_drag for a wl_data_source">
        Create an xdg_toplevel_drag for a drag and drop operation that is
        starting. This request can only be made on sources used in drag-and-drop,
        so it must be performed before wl_data_device.start_drag. Attempting
        to use the source after it has been used for a clipboard selection is a
        client error. The compositor may also require a minimum version of the
        data device manager to use this. Compositors should not consider
        xdg_toplevel_drag_manager_v1 to be supported if they do not support the
        minimum version.
      </description>
      <arg name="data_source" type="object" interface="wl_data_source"
        summary="The data source used for the drag-and-drop operation"/>
      <arg name="xdg_toplevel_drag" type="new_id"
        interface="xdg_toplevel_drag_v1"
        summary="The xdg_toplevel_drag object"/>
    </request>
  </interface>

  <interface name="xdg_toplevel_drag_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="Object representing a toplevel move during a drag">
      An object that allows a toplevel to be moved during a drag-and-drop
      operation.
    </description>

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="invalid_source" value="0"
        summary="data_source was already used for another toplevel drag"/>
      <entry name="toplevel_destroyed" value="1"
        summary="the toplevel was destroyed before the drag ended"/>
    </enum>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy an xdg_toplevel_drag object">
        Destroy this xdg_toplevel_drag object. This request must only be called
        after the data source object that was given to get_xdg_toplevel_drag
        has been destroyed or if the toplevel drag has already ended.
        Destroying this object while a drag is active does not affect the drag.
        Drag events should be sent to the wl_data_source object, and clients
        should handle drops through the wl_data_source cancelled/action_failed
        event.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="attach">
      <description summary="Attach a toplevel to this drag">
        Request that the compositor detaches the current toplevel and starts a
        drag-and-drop operation with the toplevel being dragged. The drag must
        have been started on the toplevel being the drag origin in
        wl_data_device.start_drag.

        If the toplevel is destroyed before the drag ends, the compositor should
        treat this as the toplevel becoming the drag icon for the remainder of
        the drag. The offset describes where in the window the grab point is,
        allowing the compositor to position the window correctly in relation to
        the cursor. The offset is in local (surface) coordinate of the toplevel
        surface.
      </description>
      <arg name="toplevel" type="object" interface="xdg_toplevel"
        summary="The toplevel to drag"/>
      <arg name="x_offset" type="int"
        summary="Dragged surface x offset"/>
      <arg name="y_offset" type="int"
        summary="Dragged surface y offset"/>
    </request>
  </interface>
</protocol>
